Sorry about that, so the recording caught out, but yeah, it's just going to go right back into it.
Of course, if there's a weakness in bids here, right?
So if there's a weakness in bids here, and there's some kind of strength in sellers, or just a, forget the strength, there's just a normal bit of weakness in bids here.
Right, so pick up those bids, they won't be able to push past the normal amount of selling pressure going on.
And then naturally, you know, because sellers need buyers to fill the oil,
orders, okay, if a constant stream of sellers keep coming in at the natural rate of the
market or whatever the natural rate is for that particular point in time, but there's
just a bitter weakness on the bids, all you need is a kind of just a small nudge. And then
once you get beneath this kind of infantry of where buyers are resting, it causes a shift
in the momentum. And this goes into a bearish state, okay? And it can continue in a
very state depending on what time frame is speaking up, how far prices traveled, the state
liquidity and runs like this etc etc also just to have a look at this can you see
how the base the shelf is close right close to the apex base first of all you know
when you zoom out this then forms the higher time frame apex base okay but when we're
actually monitoring and trading managing our trade we want to be able to differentiate
between okay this the high they're the inventory of buyers holding up
price and you know we want the inventory to get we can we want the inventory to be consumed
you actually want the inventory to be invalidated, all as a mechanism of, yeah, not a mechanism,
we're not fucking all that, all as a variable that increases the probability of our trades in
this instance, which would be assured, okay, and to increase the probability of the Apex-based
retest, to increase the probability of this cluster, seen a potential response there, okay?
But yeah, I kind of a side trick there. So when you have a shelf close to the Apex, look,
at the the how this is clustered okay this is clustered you see a narrower and narrower and narrower
values but it's still generally quite clustered so inside here if you're candle watching okay
each candle as it's forming you know you're gonna have an r tax what you want to be doing
it's really kind of ignoring the intracandum volatility and seeing the
trangeload state okay of this price one okay or buy is stronger or sellers
stronger, which side is getting dealt off.
What needs to happen for your trade to remain valid?
In this case, the high needs to hold.
What needs to happen for you to take this apex-based retest?
Or generally, I want this to have picked up a higher time frame level and or price
to have been validated the shelf, which tells me that buys a week.
And then if price draws back up there, you know, there is an apex-based retest trade.
Now, that is just a lower time for it.
Okay, we're just going to go straight onto, actually, the, the,
shelves that are a bit further away from price.
Okay, a shelf that is a bit further away from price.
Okay.
They're actually going to happen when price has moved really,
really inefficient at the height.
So let's just look at this example.
This is what other shelf is there, right?
You have an apex, but there's actually no other shelf
close to price.
Okay, and then what we have to contend with
is if price extends straight back down to this level,
just pretend this is a one-minute chart,
let's just pretend it's not there's a very high probability of the price coming
right back on you okay so what we want to see if a shelf is far away what I want
to see if the shelf is far away from price is for price to do this coming to
it it's gonna draw back up the extension leg but to be absorbed inside the
most local bit up inventory for sell side come down draw right back on
and effectively go deeper and deeper and deeper into the level okay now
price goes to the weaker side so if there was a strong
you have liquidity here can see you just comes right to this top side of that fractal it would have
shot it's as simple as that okay but they just couldn't um but yeah so in this case he absorbs
it quite nicely so if i was seeing this kind of absorption it'd give me a reason to stay in my
trade if i was sure well of course i would be continuously saying to myself okay
it needs to maintain this structure what does the structure look like well it's stay stepping
down every time it's moved and the most local way of inventory on cell side has absorbed this level
But the point I'm making here is, if a shelf is a bit further away from price and there is that kind of skinny leg extension,
there is a very, you know, a decent chance for price to just extend right back into it.
And this leg, the further it travels for the downside, the weaker it's getting.
All it needs is a bit of liquidity on the by side, a bit of mass on the by side, and it will push it right back up.
Once you get past this beer of inventory on a fractal basis of the move that came down,
If this, of course, this is extending really inefficiently, it's picking up just a normal bit
of mass on the by side. Once you get above this inventory of that move down, it's going to result
in a mini-momentum shift. And then that allows price to travel further and further and further.
And then we're going to have to observe this leg getting inefficient extent, etc. Or drying out.
But in this case, you see, buy flows dry out, apex is flipped, price doesn't. Because there's
hardly any buy-side liquidity inside here and you know it does maintain this efficient structure
that means that sell volume is pushing along with price we don't actually get the apex retest
that sometimes we want okay maybe a better scenario for the apex retest can you see how
price invalidates this shelf down here it comes into a residual base actually the point of release
really when liquidity dropped off and they released it would actually been probably a great
trade if price came right back into that i think there's a candle there as well
It would actually be in great trade.
Of course, we would have wanted that efficient extension.
We could observe the fractal apex inside there, just like, yeah, so we could observe the fractal
apex inside there, of course, you know, for price to do this business.
The only reason I've got this green line drawn on, this is a key point I wanted to make as
well.
Just like you have apex at the highs, okay, let's go back to the anatomy for price ring, pay
with me.
right okay so when you have okay remember how we said price is fractal you have self
similarity on multiple time frames and multiple scales and all the features of a price one can be
present anyway at any given time okay on some kind of scale that will be just like you can get
an apex consolidation on the top of the liquidity race okay because if we would to zoom into this
part it'd be the same characteristics of a height the same parameter right
prices fractal and sell some of the patterns if you take this apex consolidation you can
have it at the lows okay you can have it at the lows like that okay let's have a
look at a few of those examples so show price oh we'll have a look at this
particular example here is the the clean breaking point of this apex we'll go
into clean breaking points next but that's just the apex consolidation top and price
released out of it okay now throughout this whole liquidity base it was
transactions going on okay it's slightly it's a drift it's a consolidation
it's apex consolidation it's just a reverse apex consolidation at the
low now what's happening here is price has found bids and they continue to
bid it there will have been some bids coming in here as well until one side of
this range was weakened because of how far prices travel on the sell
side and of course bids there was a small lunge a relative surge in terms of how many offers
are available how many sellers are available that there was a by side surge and it triggered the
price response so it basically leaves an area of liquidity inside this base and in the last
literally the last video the one that cut off i did say when you have a consolidation on the lower
time frame and liquidity base generally you can just draw it all because this was only 4.2 pips
Now if this was a higher timeframe, what you're then likely going to get, you see at this
clean breaking point, there's going to be a very clear observable accumulation which pushed past
the top side of the fractal there, okay, on the top side of liquidity base there, there'd be a
very, very, very observable point of release. Okay, so if we're trading higher time frame basis,
the range of this will likely be 50, 20, 30, 60, 100 pips, depending on the time frame.
and then we want to refine also high time frame liquidity bases have more liquidity and
volume being transacted in them and of course we can then zoom in through the window of price which
is the long time frame so generally you know if it was a higher time frame level i would need to see
an accumulation which pushed price higher and that's the only way i take this long but in this instance
if i was to zoom out this is just simply a five minute base right and i don't need to be that precise
inside here, I'm just making a point, okay, for argument's sake, higher time frame basis,
we do need to refine them. We do need to look for the individual features and components
that help us categorize where liquidity is inside the liquidity base. There's three parts
to a liquidity base, top, middle, bottom. Okay, sometimes, you know, the middle and bottom
are very close together. So the point of release can be very, very close to the height. And I love
those okay because then I know we've got a clean breaking point and then we've got an
accumulation as well very very close the price I love them I look for decent response
provided you know price extended out of it inefficiently and then that means
that they extend into an inefficiency very like inefficiently kills an inefficient
extension of vulnerable or inefficient legs are vulnerable and it can trigger a
pretty decent response now in this case came to the top side
Okay, off the fractal, picked your 75 pips, and it triggers a response.
Now, for one minute, bear with you.
Right, so I just pause the recording because I'm trying to collect my force and gather my force together.
I just wanted to make, because there was something I wasn't remembering that I wanted to talk about in this video,
but I remembered it, okay?
So ultimately, the point I made earlier in the last video that you can have the small apex consolidation inside the broader one.
Okay, now this is really, really, really important.
So what we've covered is a shelf far away from price.
away from price number one a shelf close the price why I haven't also we've
covered if price does travel to a shelf that's further away from price you know
we can extend into it efficiently in this this this time it invalidated it
but it still comes into a feeding slash residual fractal the nature of the
extension left it when the ball and price draws right back in but the point I
was making okay at that point in time was
the I was trying to make anyway, the bigger the apex, okay, consolidation, so I would argue that this whole area is an apex consolidation, okay? So this whole area is an apex consolidation. The bigger the apex consolidation, what that means is, it's dealing with a bigger chunk, okay, a bigger inventory, a higher time frame base. Again, that's a principle, higher time frame levels, pooled more liquidity. It's dealing with a bigger chunk. It's dealing with a bigger chunk. It's a bigger inventory.
chunk holding the shelf up okay the the the shelf basically right the liquidity inside the
the shell holding price up all that means is once you flip a higher time frame level it's going
to result in a more of a profound shift in the state of liquidity okay so in this case we have a
fractal price swing base police price pause continuation leg high inefficient extension
slightly jumpy sorry here's your shell that happens to be lining got sorry there's your shell which
happens to be lining up right with the apex base okay and then this is a smaller fractal apex
within this overall apex and this is how we differentiate so if i'm looking to go short which i
would most definitely look to go short on a leg like this okay which releases after the
price has traveled higher on the higher time frame and then it's releasing on the lower time frame
like this provided i can identify your level it's refined i've anticipated prior to it and then
prices and i've also anticipated the pain trade the feeding factor past it um provided i can do that
when i get this kind of extension straight running like this is really telling me that you know
we're running dry on liquidity because that's a very key characteristic of a high this level does
come into a daily feeding factor by the way so what i would be doing i take the first touch short i take the
first touch short, wherever my level happened to be, right? And then I would be looking to
see, first of all is the height in. Then where is this small apex holding this leg higher,
this leg up? Okay, so I'm not concerned with the broader state yet, because what I've got
a contend with is the inventory here. Once I start to see this breakdown, okay, notice absorb
inside the high, then we go deeper in validating this little apex, draws back into the
inventory, all fitting the parameters and characteristics of a high.
then get the breakdown, okay?
Now, that doesn't, once I'm past this low,
once price is past this low,
that doesn't tell me that we're going,
because this is picking up a daily level,
that doesn't confirm to me yet, okay,
that price gonna come down here,
because we still have this higher time frame H1 base
to contend with.
It's only when you flip that higher time frame base, okay,
which happens to be at this apex consolidation,
only then we're going to see a bigger, more profound shift
in the state of liquidity.
And what that means is, if this is a bigger shell,
it's going to have more liquidity.
And if it has more liquidity, it's very likely
we're going to stay and maintain a bigger apex consolidation
than the one we've seen there.
So when this apex broke down, it only meant that price
going to fill in this leg down to here, here,
and gladly it invalidated the shelf, which
a bigger sign to us that buyers are running dry because of how fast sellers are extending
to find buyers but again this is known why does it come right back higher well look at the extension
extensions get filled and efficient price acting is vulnerable it's meeting just a normal
massive liquidity by this point this leg has run dry volatility is a function of liquidity
and you know bomb draw you right back higher and then you know why did price not react off that level
well it did okay it did react but it just kept getting absorbed right back inside the most
local base for buyers it was kind of stair stepping higher what that means is there's not
enough sell-side liquidity inside these levels it was covered in the midflow midflow
mid-flow price pause videos earlier in the series what it does end up doing is let's just take
a look at it this is fucking awesome right just look at this right here there's your shelf
price invalidates it releases it comes into this base okay and again this is five
minutes so whatever you know it comes into that and then by this point we already
know that this is picked up or is picking up whatever inventory of liquidity
is around this shelf you actually poked past it which is a good sign for us and then
released inefficiently there's a few few principles going on here you know price
goes to the weaker side well this already told of it is is weak because of
the fact that you validated the shell and then it released so extensions get filled
extends extending by the past its hide inefficient legs are vulnerable and also in this case what
would have price been what was price doing there's your shell price pumped through it
is drawing back up for a shelf retest okay so there's many many components going on here and i love
these ranges okay so i actually probably make more money in these kind of ranges than i would
a trending environment like this.
Okay, let me just show you another example.
This is a higher time frame on, okay.
Boom, this.
And there's a few more cable here.
This is your high.
This is your H4 apex base.
And of course there's an apex base here.
100% is an apex base here.
That's just on the lower timeframe.
So when that lower time frame makes the apex flipped
that doesn't say basically shit
about price flipping this H4 base.
How we would determine if price is likely
to flip this H4 base
or to absorb the H4 shelf, sorry.
This is picking up a weekly level.
Price, just the overall dynamics
of how far price travels to find buyers here,
then released inefficiently.
Basically, we could then start anticipating
this weekly level that's being injected
and picked up the price, being injected in price
to pressure this higher time frame show.
But yeah, point of making is
there's an apex inside there of course okay but that doesn't actually mean price is
gonna flip this H4 shell until you know you've gauged the polar state of
equality you can see how price hangs around in here once you flipped beneath that
apex where's it go straight to your day apex base okay and then you see price
pick you up go on the price run pick up this daily this daily level here goes in another
price run deeper into the shelf draws right back inside the pick-up of the
daily which came from here which came from there and of course it goes even
deeper draws right back up into this level grabbing the bottom side and then
finally it goes in a decent price run down but again the nature of this
price run down it comes into this fractal here because of the nature of this
extension extensions are vulnerable price picks up a mass of buyers
even if this is residual that's kind of a that kind of a quality base at that
point in time. But even if that's residual, okay, on a relative basis to this price swing,
even if that is residual, because of the nature of this extension down, that leg was left
vulnerable. Why did this leg extend down the way they did? Well, we kind of had a clean release
there. Okay. Now, the point I'm making here is price came down and efficiently, even the leg
exposed, picked up by from the top side clean breaking point here, and then once it flipped above
this shelf the inventory of cell-side liquidity here that resulted in a profound shift okay now what
that means is even though this is a weak buy level the nature and the the sparsity of liquidity in the
inefficient leg left it vulnerable and the there was enough liquidity in the residual level to
push past the inventory of sellers which was at this free narrow now what that means is
price can have to likely travel to unfilled liquidity
on build liquidity
to generate a shift
on this extension
and where does it go
it comes into this level
and profoundly remember catching up short
and then Friday Fockeries
Friday continued
literally came to the top side
of this fractal here
whilst
we maintained and remained
below this H4 shelf
might well you know
so what this is really just doing
is clearing out liquidity
so another point to make here is
you can have a bias
now have your higher time
and bias what matters more is the state of equity okay what matters more is the short-term
inefficiency is a short-term weakness which is going to generate responses for us and all we care about
responses when you're in the realm of being able to take both sides of the market you're used to
execute and you from the exercises that is when you know you're going to be taking these lungs
probably closing them taking shorts realizing it's not working and then you catch this really
good trade and you I just this is you know many many people are going to
watch this video have already so not many the people that are watching this
video probably now will remember me talking about this high continuing to
downside but again that's beside the point so as comes and picks up on door
liquidity and again you know so this is another example of a shelf a bit further
away from price there we go okay so this is a shelf a bit further away from
price price extended it could have easily extended and efficiently let's go
looking at 60 minute okay so you know it's coming into some fractal
insurresponder and we came past it and it's basically formed a price pause it's not
clean price pause here but by that point price is already invalidated this show
this has already picked up a day fractal we got beneath the apex base
a few things could happen if this came i would say right down then that
leg would likely get filled okay we could have easily done that but in the case it doesn't
So the characteristics in price do give a lot away what's likely to happen.
And once you go up beneath this shelf here, look what happens.
It goes into midflow.
It goes into the price pause, continuation, pause, continuation,
come back, continuation, et cetera, for like 13, from the high to that low,
about 13 days straight.
Okay.
So here's another example of a higher time frame, show a bigger apex space,
but I was still a smaller one there as well.
So Price came and picked up a residual level inside here.
Flip the apex.
There's a H1 shut there.
Okay, but there's a day, this is visible on the daily.
This H4, I know, but this is visible on the daily.
Price had to contend with that.
It had to contend, contend.
And then it comes right back to the apex.
That's an apex-based retest, which is going to cover in the next video.
Same applies with this.
I want to show you on daily, right?
Because that makes more sense.
Basically, the point I'm making is when you're forming daily apex consolidation,
These are rallies on the lower time frame. This is probably a mini value. They're tradable. Okay, and it basically means price can stay in this consolidation for longer than you would see on the five minute, the one hour, but it's better trading conditions. Okay, they're still good trading conditions. And what I like to see is basically price form rallies, but that keep on getting consumed by buyers, by sellers, sorry. And then once you flip the Ipex, there's a profound shift.
Okay, so you clearly see price was sitting on top of this area, okay, but price came to the feeding factor here, let's see, okay, what does it end up doing from here? It goes down here, picks up by new liquidity. Also, the top is picked, consuming the bottom, running it higher. Because of the nature of that extension, what would happen in this pickup? It would have resulted in a main shift and the momentum on this leg down because of the nature of the extension that was weak. And then that
allowed price to draw back up for the thickest point of liquidity and again in this
base the bottom side was picked came to the top okay and here liquidity drops off a bit
the shot price runs okay and of course when it's trending so in this case it's trending
you can expect new lows okay again this is all hindsight you can get more context
trading life conditions yeah that's about it for this particular video um they will make one
yeah sorry so that's about it for this particular video um
And then the next one we're going to talk about Apex re-tests.
I can probably be at 5'10 and it's gone.
And then, you know, we're going to the relevant structures next.
But there's a lot of nuggets in this particular video on the last one.
And all the other ones in the series, there's many, many nuggets.
Watch them over, engage, find your niche.
Just continue to build that understanding.
Okay, nice one.